Bobby Baker
Microservices Engineer

Global,

+1-513-404-4499

bob@arvo.technology

http://bobbybakes.github.io/

English

BACKGROUND

ABOUT

A Senior Software Engineer with over 10 years of engineering experience and 5 years of experience in the development and architecture of cloud based solutions. A versatile engineer with expertise in cross-platform products, security protocols, and efficient data solutions. Accomplished in leading teams to deliver solid systems and applying best practices in software development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Microservices Engineer, ETCH

Sep, 2021 - Present

Microservices Architecture / Development

• Architected and developed event based cloud solutions to provide secure APIs and real time data solutions in the transportation industry.

Blockchain Hackathon -2nd Place Winner,

Jun, 2021 - Jul, 2021 16 days

IBC Challenge: Build a blockchain application that utilizes IBC, or build a novel use case for the IBC protocol.

- Built in Go, this project is designed to demonstrate the use of IBC between different zones in the Cosmos ecosystem for privacy preserving credential management.
- https://github.com/whalelephant/CertX

Mobile Engineer, X-Team - RIOT GAMES

Dec, 2020 - Dec, 2021 1 year

Swift / Kotlin

- o Converted Android / iOS to KMM Shared Libraries.
- Fixed legacy iOS issues.
- SwiftUI development.
- Fixed legacy Android issues.

Microservices Engineer - Fox Broadcasting, X-Team

Sep, 2018 - Oct, 2020 2 years 1 month

Go / Node Microservices Development

- Developed Microservices in Node.js and GoLang in AWS to serve low-latency streaming to platforms such as web and native devices.
- Responsible for migrating Node.js Microservices to GoLang.

Software Journeyman / Microservices Engineer, Pillar Technology - Honda Automotive

Mar, 2018 - Sep, 2018 6 month

Extreme Programming

- · Architected and developed a Big Data platform to advance data science and improve deep learning algorithms.
- Built with AWS and Hadoop, developed ETL (Extract, Transform, And Load) solutions to extract vehicle data to be loaded into Virtual Machines.
- Built with AWS and Jupiter notebook. developed solutions to allow Data Scientists to analysis on vehicle data to glean incites on driver activity.

Software Journeyman / Microservices Engineer, Pillar Technology - Ford Automotive / Columbus Collaboratory

Oct, 2016 - Sep, 2018 1 year 10 months

Extreme Programming

- Developed applications and provided agile consulting on an embedded software project in the automotive industry.
- Developed a cyber security solution, using advanced analytics to aggregate and identify malicious threats and vulnerabilities.

Senior Developer, IT Applications, Nationwide Insurance

Aug, 2014 - Oct, 2016 2 years 2 months

J2EE, customer-facing web applications

- o Tech Lead / Mentor
- o Java / Spring MVC

GIS Analyst and Software Developer, Stantec

Apr, 2012 - Aug, 2014 2 years 4 months

GIS Development and Analytical Cartography

- o Interactive Mapping Applications and Add-ons
- FEMA floodplain mapping
- Cartography

GIS Specialist, The Ohio Department of Natural Resources

Jan, 2008 - Apr, 2012 4 years 3 months

GIS Analyst

· Groundwater Resource Mapping

SKILLS

Dev Ops

Native Development Flutter ReactNative Android iOS API Development Golang Python NodeJS MEAN Mongo Express Angular 1/2 Node J2EE WebSphere Java JSP Gradle Maven Groovy Spring MVC Microservices Vert.x AWS LINKERD Nginx Serverless.io Big Data

